op
ED
本字幕由诸神字幕组（kamigami.org）制作，仅供交流学习，禁止用于任何商业用途
日听:aimie king  翻译:念白白 poopy   校对:木落  时间轴:小涩
Before I kill you, I'll ask you a question.
殺す前に一つだけ聞いておこう
You're with the Insect Hunters,
so why protect the princess?
蟲狩りの貴様がなぜ姫君の為に戦っている
I have nothing to say...
蟲ケラに語る言葉など　無い
to an insect!
Then die!
ならば　死ね
I have seen through your every illusion.
貴様の幻術は全て見切った
I feel so much better in this form,
don't you, Kamanosuke?
やはりこっちの方がしっくり来るのう　鎌之介
You're looking pretty sickly now.
随分と優男になったものね
I like it. They're serious now.
いいね　ようやく本気を出しやがったか
I won't lose!
負けない
さーて　お主達　続きと行こうか
Now, then... Time for round two!
Sounds good to me.
上等だぜ
Matsukichi! Tamekichi!
末吉　為吉 急急如律令
Do my bidding!
あんた達は　ここで倒す
We'll defeat you here!
The Insect Magistrate's
Cursed Past
真田幸村
Sanada Yukimura!
今度の鼠はちと貧相だな
This rat is a little scrawny.
Do your best, little rat.
精々気張れよ　小鼠
The last rat,
さっきの鼠
the samurai with the quick draw,
was at least enough to entertain me.
居合いの武士は暇つぶし程度には楽しませてくれたぞ
What do you mean?!
どういう事だ
わからぬか
You don't understand?
ま　まさか
Y-You can't mean...
Oooka-dono!
大岡殿
聞こえますか　大岡殿
Can you hear me, Oooka-dono?!
そんなはずは無い
That's impossible!
Oooka-dono is a true samurai.
大岡殿は誠の武士
He could never lose to an
evil creature like you!
貴様のような悪に屈するなどあるはず無い
How stupid.
くだらんな
What?
なに
At every turn, you samurai speak of justice,
貴様ら武士は何かと言えば正義を振りかざすが
but what is the reality?
現実はどうだ
You can protect no one.
何も守れず　誰も救えず
You can save no one.
我らの前に膝を屈するばかりではないか
Before us, you merely fall to your knees.
The draw-skill samurai was no different.
居合いの武士とて同じよ
His arm was torn off and he was
crawling along the ground.
腕を捥がれ無様に地べたを 這いずり回っておったわ
貴様
Why, you...
What is this weak blade?
なんだそのぬるい剣は
Tsukishima!
月島
Yukimura...
幸村
It brings back so many memories
to see you again, Princess Naa.
お懐かしゅうございます　奈阿姫様
I am deeply honored to see you.
この様に姫と顔合わせができ
この幸村　光栄の極み
So let us leave for our castle...
では参りましょう
我らの城　王のおわす大阪城へ
For Oosaka Castle, where the king waits.
I have a task I must complete.
妾には大切な勤めがある
I shall not accompany you.
お主と行動を共にするつもりは　無い
Very well.
そうですか
ならば　この手でお連れするまでの事
Then I shall take you there.
My king will soon awaken.
我が王は間もなくお目覚めです
さ　一刻も早く大阪へ
Now, come with me to Oosaka.
Miss!
お付きの方
月島流　富嶽鉄槌割り
Tsukishima-style: Mt. Fuji Hammer!
Get to the Well now, miss!
今のうちに　早く井戸に行ってください
お付きの方
To think you'd try to fight me
with such weak power...
この程度の力で俺に立ち向かおうとはな
Miss, don't worry.
お付きの方　ご安心ください
I, Tsukishima Jinbei, shall protect
you, even at the cost of my life!
月島仁兵衛　この命に代えてもお守り致します
You're wasting your time.
くだらん足掻きを
You'll die for nothing, like that samurai
with the quick-draw swordsmanship.
居合いの武士と同じく無駄死に終わるだけだぞ
Die for nothing?
無駄死にだと
Oooka-dono was a samurai among samurai.
大岡殿こそ　武士の中の武士
And when you mock him,
それを愚弄する貴様は
大バツだ
you're very wrong!
Tsukishima-style: Mt. Fuji Storm!
月島流　富嶽山嵐
Plus...
プラス　富嶽　鉄槌割り
Mt. Fuji Hammer!
月島
Tsukishima...
I shall go, then.
では行くぞ
The Eternal Insects.
常世の蟲
"Do not break the seal of the Eternal Well.
汝　常世の井戸の封印を解く勿れ
Only those who have overcome their painful pasts
悲しみの過去に打ち勝つ者のみ
力を取り戻すであろう　か
will recover their power," is it?
Very well.
良かろう
I did it...
やった
Wh-What's this?
こ　これは
Tsukishima-dono, what happened?
月島殿　一体何が
I defeated Sanada Yukimura!
真田幸村を　討ち果たしました
You defeated Yukimura?
なんと　あの幸村を
はい
Yes!
Where is the princess?
姫は
Inside the Well!
井戸の中へ
What's this?
これは
Princess Naa is regaining her power.
奈阿姫様が力を取り戻しておられるのだ
拙者の幻術を見切っただと
You've seen through my illusions?
Interesting.
面白い
You will now become an insect, body and soul!
貴様はこれより身も心も蟲となる
A fitting ending for an Insect Hunter
数多の蟲を殺してきた　蟲狩りの貴様にこそふさわしい末路であろう
that has slain so many of us.
Great Forbidden Technique: Insect Resurrection!
大禁術　蟲返り
It appears that using your illusions to
attack also weakens your defenses.
幻術を攻めに使うと守りは甘くなるようだな
I-Impossible...
ば　バカな
太秦は　神とも神と聞こえくる
"Uzumasa took his blade,
常世の神を打ち懲ますも
and he slew the greatest of
the Eternal Land's gods."
塵外刀強化　刀蟲化合
Enhanced Jingaitou: Insect Fusion!
I'll take your insect power.
貴様の蟲の力を頂く
真田の未来を消し去るために
To destroy Sanada's future!
You bastard!
貴様
It's time to go.
行くか
To defeat the insects within Kishuu Castle.
紀州の城に巣くう　蟲を退治に
Sanada Yukimura!
真田幸村
よもや　あの程度で俺を倒せたと
Did you really think that would
be enough to defeat me?
Delay Sanada until Princess Naa
can regain all of her power!
奈阿姫様が力を取り戻すまで 真田を足止めするのだ
Yes, sir.
はっ
It's funny, how little you know...
何も知らぬとは滑稽なものだな
What?
なに
Very well.
まー良い
Then try to delay me.
精々足止めとやらに励むが良い
Watch out...
危ない
Please dodge!
避けてください
Sanada Yukimura...
真田幸村
He's stronger than any foe I've ever faced.
これまで立ち会ったどの敵よりも強い
But I am a samurai and I will
keep winning until I die.
だが自分は死ぬまで勝ち続ける武士
そして　自分の後ろには　守るべき人がいる
And there are people behind
me that I must protect.
Prepare to die, Sanada Yukimura!
真田幸村　覚悟を
月島流　富嶽鉄槌割り
Tsukishima-style: Mt. Fuji Hammer!
そんな技ではこの幸村を倒せぬ
You'll never defeat me with a technique like that.
But I'll give you this, little rat.
だが褒めてやるぞ　小鼠
You've entertained me as much
as the quick draw practitioner.
居合いの武士程には楽しませてもらったわ
Tsukishima-dono!
月島殿
毒に悶え　苦しみながら死ぬと良い
Die in agony from the poison.
No, Princess!
姫様　いけません
Please give it here.
こちらにお渡しください
No!
いやじゃ
こ　これは
What's this?
What is this scene?
何だ　この風景は
あの少女　お付の方と瓜二つだ
That girl... She looks just like the servant.
What's going on?
何の騒ぎじゃ
Father! Mother!
ててさま　かかさま
Everyone was being mean to
Insect-san, so I saved him.
皆が蟲さんをいじめていたから　助けてあげたの
Look.
見て　こんなにされて可哀相に
The poor thing...
Princess Naa...
奈阿姫
What are you doing?
何をしておる　はやお取り上げ
Take it from her!
しかし
But...
There's nothing to fear.
怖がることはない　わらわが守ってやるぞ
I will protect you.
When she's being that way, she won't listen.
ああなると聞きませぬ
It's fine...
仕方ないのう
Father!
ててさま
It's no good!
だめです　全軍全滅です
We've been annihilated!
Our army is finished!
わが軍はもはや
さ　お逃げ
Now, run away.
だめじゃ　お主とはもう一緒にいられないのじゃ
No!
I can't stay with you!
この城は　もうまもなく敵の手に落ちる
This castle will soon fall to the enemy.
And then, I shall...
そうなればわらわは…
Farewell, cute Insect-san!
さようなら　可愛い蟲さん
Princess Naa!
奈阿姫
Where are you, Princess Naa?
奈阿姫　どこにいるのじゃ
Huh? Where am I?
あれ　わらわは
Father? Mother?
ててさま　かかさま　どこ
Where am I?
The enemy is using poison...
敵が毒をまいたぞ　上様をお守りするのだ
Protect the princess!
You guys...
お前達
What happened?
どうしたのじゃ
奈阿姫　どこにおる
Where are you, Princess Naa?
If you can hear me, answer!
聞こえたら返事をしておくれ
Father! Mother!
ててさま　かかさま
Run, my lord—
上様　お逃げください
What are you?!
何じゃ　貴様は
来るな　来るでない
Stay away!
Stay back!
ててさま　怒っちゃいやなのじゃ
Father, don't be angry...
わらわは蟲さんを外に
I'm taking the insect outside.
く　来るな
Stay back!
What's wrong?
どうしたの
Stay away...
来るでない
ち　力　力って
P-Power?
What do you mean by "power"?
どういうこと
You gave me your power?
お前の力を　わらわに
Then, this is...
では　これは　わらわが
I did this?
いや
No!
Tsukishima?
月島
Why are you here?
お主　なぜここに
M-Miss...
お　お付の方
Did you see my past?
見たのか　過去を
わらわの忌まわしい過去を
My horrible past?
Disaster comes to everyone around me.
皆不幸になるのじゃ
わらわのそばにいる者は 皆不幸になるのじゃ
Everyone.
I was foolish...
愚かであった
Everything began then.
すべてはあの時始まってしまったのだ
And all because I took pity on that insect.
蟲などに情けなどかけたばかりに
That isn't true!
それは　違います
Your kindness in trying to protect
that insect was right!
蟲を守ろうとするお付の方の優しいお気持ちは正しかったのです
What?
何を
小さきもの　弱気ものを守ることが間違っているというのなら
If you say protecting the small
and the weak is wrong,
then the whole world is wrong.
それは　その世界が間違っているのです
自分には想像もできないほどお辛いこともあったでしょう
I'm sure you've endured more
pain than I can imagine.
しかし　正しきことを成したお付の方には
But you did the right thing, so a
right future surely awaits you!
必ずや正しき未来が待っているはず  自分はそう信じています
I believe that.
月島
Tsukishima...
You're warm...
暖かいな
Why are you so warm?
どうしてお主はこんなにも暖かいのじゃ
感じるか　わらわの胸の鼓動を
Can you feel my heart beating?
Y-Yes...
あっ　はい
You gave this to me.
これは　お主がくれたのじゃ
For a century, my heart was frozen...
わらわの心は　百年冷たく凍っておった
And you were the one who
melted it, Tsukishima.
それを融かしてくれたのは
月島　お主じゃ
Your smile...
お主の笑顔が
Your warmth...
ぬくもりが
How many times they've
made my heart flutter...
わらわの心を幾たび振るわせたことか
今もこの胸に染み入っておる
That warmth still fills my heart.
This is human kindness, isn't it?
これが人の優しさなのだな
Thank you, Tsukishima.
ありがとう　月島
こちらこそ　ありがとうございます
And I thank you!
笑顔にお力をいただいているのは　自分も同じ
I gain power from your smile, as well.
Oharu-dono, Hibachi-dono,
Koikawa-dono and Tenma-dono...
お春殿や　火鉢殿
恋川殿に　天間殿
And Mugai-dono...
無涯殿は　あまり笑ってくれませんが
He doesn't really smile much.
But your smile gives me so much power!
お付の方の笑顔で　力がどんどん漲ってまいります
Now, let's do our best at our tasks.
さ　お務めを頑張りましょう
I, Tsukikishima Jinbei,
will follow you to the end!
この月島仁兵衛　最後までお供を致します
お主のお務めがここまでじゃ
Your task ends here.
お主がくれたぬくもりは　忘れぬぞ
I shall never forget the warmth
you have given me.
M-Miss!
お　お付の方
お付の方
This is a sign that Princess Naa has
completely regained her power!
これはまさに奈阿姫様が完全なる力を取り戻しておられる証
What's so funny?
何がおかしい
The princess regaining her power
within the Eternal Well
姫君が常世の井戸で力を取り戻すのは
is exactly what we wanted.
むしろこちらが望んだこと
なっ
What?
When the princess completely regains her power,
完全なる力を取り戻した姫は
she and my king will wipe
humanity from this land.
わが王とともにこの国から人間共を根絶やしにするのだ
What nonsense is this?
何をバカな
常世の井戸が何の代償もなく蟲に力を与えると思うのか
Do you think the Eternal Well grants
insects power without a price?
常世の井戸は与える力によって
They say it takes memories.
And the greater the power it bestows,
the more it will take...
その記憶を奪っていくという
Should the princess regain her entire power,
姫君がすべての力を取り戻せば
she will lose all of her memories!
すなわちすべての記憶を失うのだ
お　お付の方の記憶が…なくなる
H-Her memories will disappear?
Our last hope...
われらの最後の希望が
No...
そんな
You lose, humans.
貴様らの負けだ　人間
火鉢殿　お付の方を褌で井戸から引き上げます
Next Time
Hibachi-dono, I'll use your loincloth
to pull the servant from the Well!
Remove it!
お脱ぎください
Okay, sure...
オーケー　するする
って脱ぐわけないでしょうが
Of course I won't do that!
Next time, on Mushibugyou:
次回　蟲奉行「交わした約束は絶望の中の希望」
The Promise Is Hope Within Despair.
The Promise Is Hope Within Despair